#現在帶王剛兄弟去摘一下攝影小哥家的板栗
Now we take our buddy Wang Gang to pick the chestnuts at Mr. Cameraman's place.
#他家的板栗太多啦 吃不完他家
He has too many! He just can't finish.
#對 走
Sure! Let's go!
#這次你們家的魚放過啦 板栗不能放過
We already have no chance on your fish. We can't miss your chestnuts.
#走走走 走走 就在那邊
Go go go! This way!
#現在我們到啦 你看 這個板栗都熟啦
Now we have arrived. See? The chestnuts are all ready.
#像[SIC]我們招手了它
They are waving at us.
#我去拿棍子 在這裡有
I'll get a rod. It's over there.
#這個 敲這個板栗要小心一點
You know, you need to very careful while knocking down the chestnuts.
#要不你看著我敲就行
Or you just watch me knock?
#好 我在上面給你接著
Alright! I will catch the chestnuts up there.
#接 哈哈哈
Catch? Ha ha ha!
#你確定你要接著嗎
Are you sure that you are catching?
#用這個接
Yea, using this.
#打得下來嗎
Can they be knocked down?
#我要上樹上去摘 這樣旁邊敲 敲不了兩個的
I will climb up the tree. I can hardly get any by knocking here.
#這樣
Let me see...
#我看一下你個樹怎麼上去
How can I climb this tree?
#誒 這裡可以上去的哦
Eh? I can climb from here.
#很好上的哦 這個
It's easy to climb, in fact.
#你看 我們爬到樹上來啦
See? We are in the tree now.
#樹上好多板栗呀
I can see a lot of chestnuts.
#都不是很老
They are still quite young.
#但是很多啊
But there are really a lot,
#又大
and they are big.
#把它撿起來
Let's pick them up.
#鞋都少了一隻
I've even dropped a slipper.
#這個為甚麼不可以用手來拿呢
Do you know why can't we pick by hands?
#呃 呃 這個用手來拿呀
Eh, eh, we pick by hands.
#我已經被扎出血了好不好
You know what? My finger is already bleeding.
#這個太那個啦 太鋒利啦
This is too, eh, I mean, too sharp.
#啊 這麼多
Ah, so many!
#我剛剛剝了一個吃 手也被扎出血
I just got my finger cut when I was peeling a chestnut.
#我來打幾個吧
Let me knock some.
#杆子呢
Where's the rod?
#太重啦 你打不動的
You can't. The rod is too heavy for you.
#好重的杆子
It's really heavy.
#打這邊哦
You can knock here.
#哦 看到了那裡 打得到嗎
Oh! I see, right over there. Shall I try?
#掉了兩個
I got two!
#兄弟家這個棍子太重啦 這個
My buddy's rod is too heavy, really.
#這個沒點體力還幹不了
It's not possible without physical strength.
#那個更黑看到沒有
That one is even more black, see?
#爆開啦
It's already broken.
#哇
Wa!
#很靚的那個
That one is very beautiful.
#呃 想吃的就自己動手啦 自己挖哦
Eh, help yourself if you want to try. Just peel it.
#自己挖自己的
Peel your own chestnuts.
#這兩個就大啊 這兩個
These two are large, these two.
#小心手
Watch your hands.
#那個刺到手很很[SIC]痛的
It really hurts if you get pricked.
#我幫你們挖啊
Let me help you.
#慢慢吃啊 就不要去惦記那個魚了啊
Enjoy the chestnuts and forget about the fish.
#你家的魚
Your fish...
#看來是吃不到啦
I don't think we have any chance.
#等一下我帶你看一個東西
Let me show you something interesting.
#看甚麼
What is it?
#我的果子上寫了名字的
My melon, with my name on it.
#就在那裡
It's just over there.
#好啦 現在天色有點晚啦 我們要回去啦
Alright. It's getting dark. We are leaving now.
#我們要回去啦
Yea, we need to go now.
#把這個沒吃完的回去打包 (註︰不清楚他想說甚麼，是打包回去，還是回去再打包，我就當作打包回去算了)
I''ll bring the rest home.
#回去慢慢吃 走吧
Yep, enjoy at home. Let's go.